Hello Guys, Welcome to my YouTube channel
Best Share Analysis.
So today we are going to talk
about an insurance company which is from a
well-known bank, whose name is
ICICI LBD General Insurance Company.  We will
know about its related news and
its Q4 results
which have come.  So now we will look at NSC
because the market is on.
Talking about NSC, the share price of ICICI DMB General
Insurance Company was
trading at Rs 1885.80 which is a
gain of around Rs 28.20 i.e. 1.52% in 1 day.
Talking about one week, there is an increase of ₹141.
If I talk about 1 month, then there is an increase of ₹36.
If we talk about 3 months, then there is an increase of ₹36
and if we talk about 6 months, then there is a
decrease of ₹123.90 which is a negative return on equity of 6.6%.
And if we talk about one year, then an
increase of ₹127 is being seen in it,
which is 7.22% of the stock.  Now let's
look at the overview, let's
look at the market honestly market depth.
54.81% from buy order, 45.9% from sell order.
Today's low set by the company is
1842.60.  Today's high has been set at
198.90.
If we talk about the 52 week low, it is set at ₹1629.50
and the high is set at ₹268.
Now let us look at its fundamentals.
So we will look at the market cap first.
Talking about market cap, it has a
market cap of Rs 92,684 crore.  It
is a large cap company.
Talking about PE ratio, it has a PE ratio of 33.89.  The
PV ratio is slightly higher at
5.62.  If we look at the industry PA, it is 16.16.
Talking about debt to equity, it is
0.00.  You will see that the debt to equity is
0.00, which is very impressive.  The
PE of WELL stock is slightly
higher compared to the rest of the industry.  It is a little double.  Here you have to
pay ₹16.16 to earn ₹1.
And here ₹33.89
and PE is also high.  So the stock
is a little bit expensive.  Talking about return on equity, it
is 16.57%.  Return on equity is good.
Talking about 16.57% EPS is 54.86.
Talking about dividend yield, it is 0.67%.
Talking about book value, it is 331.07.  The face
value is 10.  Return on equity is 16.57%.
EPS is 54.86.  Ok?  The dividend
yield is slightly lower.  And you
will see the book value of Rs 331.  But where is the stock trading
?  1885.50
p.a.   So
now let's look at the financials.
Talking about revenue, it is increasing quarterly.  If we
talk about yearly, the revenue is
increasing yearly.  If we talk about profit, it is
not stable quarterly.  But
if we talk yearly, it is increasing yearly.
This is a big sign in itself.
Talking about net worth, growth is being seen year after year.
Now if we
talk about the shareholder pattern, the promoters have a
holding of 51.31%.  Meaning this is a
good thing in itself.  So foreign institutions
have a holding of 23.35%.  Mutual funds
hold 14.959%. Retail & Others
holds 6.98%.  Other Domestic
Institutions hold 3.77%.
Overall, if you look at it, the shareholder
pattern is very good.  Because the promoters
already hold 51.31% stake.  And if we
talk about it, apart from that, all the sectors have
investment in it.  Be it FIIs, mutual
funds, retails, others, other
domestic institutions, what ever.  So if you
want, you can include it in your watch list
because its results have been excellent
and
NIC has given it new ratings among the big brokerage firms.  So,
I am not a SEBI registered analyst at all
and this is not a buy or sell stock
recommendation at all.  So, before
investing in any financial instrument, do
consult your financial advisor.  So let's look at the technicalities.
Technicals Two out of 13 are bears.  One
is neutral and 10 are bullish.  Now if we
talk about the event, its results were declared yesterday.
Apart from that, the company has also given dividend.
You will see that the dividend was announced on 14th October.
October 23rd was the X date.   Same is the case
here.  Dividend was announced on 15th April.
June 6th was the X date.  Let's go and
watch the news.  The news has come.
ICICI Bank reports in-line Q4 results
aiming to sustain return on equity.
Return on equity will remain 18 to 20% sustainable.
Company sales insights on performance
during CNBC and if you also
see here then ICICI LBD source growth in modern
and retail health insurance added by
GST cut and because of that and strong
distribution, it has
seen good growth. Motilal Oswal has
cut the target slightly from estimate but
maintained buy rating with a target of 2230.
And if we talk about Macui,
you can also see Macui's outperform rating with
2350 target. Focus on margins.
IFRS adoption option and IRDHI changes
boost financial 26 outlook. See here.
HSBC maintains buy on ICICI LBD. HSBC has
maintained a target of 2200. So this is the
rest, let's see its result. Now, ICICI
LBD General Insurance has
reported a stable performance in the fourth quarter of the financial year, in
which
net profit has
increased by 7.3% on yearly basis due to 8.2% growth in gross direct premium income (GDP).  There has been an increase of 7.3% on annual basis.
It has reached Rs 546.6 crore.  The
company has
declared a final dividend of Rs 7 per share.  Also the
combined ratio has improved.  101.2% has
decreased from 102.5% which indicates better
underwriting performance.
Net profit has increased to Rs 540.6
crore.  Or in some reports
547 crores which is an
increase of 7.3 to 7.6% compared to the previous year.  Talking about total income, it has
increased by 13.12% to Rs 6618.76
crore.  Total income grew by 8% and GDPI by
8.2%, which is
much higher than the industry growth rate of 10.9%.
This quarter's profit will increase from 102.5% in the previous year's quarter to
101.2%, reflecting improved operational
capacity.  Talking about dividend, a
final dividend of ₹7 per equity share has been approved for FY2026.
Dividend of ₹7 has also been given.
By March 31, 2026, it was 2.6 times.  The world
requirement is well above 1.50 times.
However, 2.69 on December 31, 2000
was 2.69 times on 2025.  It is a little less than that.
Retail health insurance premiums
grew by 55.65% year-on-year.  Whereas motor insurance has
increased by 6.24%.  So, if we talk about the full year
's income, it has increased by 10.5% to Rs
271.94 crore and the total income for the whole year has
increased by 12.9% to Rs 25894.94
crore.  So guys, these are the numbers for Q4.
ICICI LBAT General Insurance which is
very good.  So this was the news guys.  I was
out yesterday so I couldn't make a video.   I am
making it today.
To know more such stock related news, do not forget to
like, share and subscribe to our channel.